Engaging Father Christmas is a tv movie, romance,
drama film directed by David Winning.
It's Christmas and Miranda leaves Seattle with a suitcase full of presents to join her long- lost family
in Carlton Heath, where she will experience the joyful traditions she missed as a child.
Last Christmas, Miranda fell in love with Ian, a local man who helped her as she searched for her
father, James Whitcomb, a famous theatre actor she believed had a connection to the town.
At his widow Margaret’s request, Miranda agrees to keep it a
secret to protect the family from scandal.
Miranda Carson Chester, played by Erin Krakow.
Ian McAndrick, played by Niall Matter.
Margaret Whitcomb, played by Wendie Malick.
Andrew McAndrick, played by Michael Kopsa.
Katherine McAndrick, played by P. Lynn Johnson.
Ellie Whitcomb, played by Aliyah O'Brien.
The Father Christmas film series is an American/Canadian trilogy, starring Erin
Krakow and Niall Matter, based on the novels of Robin Jones Gunn.
The films were originally broadcast in the USA on Hallmark Movies & Mysteries, as
part of the channels' "Miracles of Christmas" seasonal programming.
The films follow the story of Miranda Chester (Krakow), as she visits the cozy sundown
town of Carlton Heath, Vermont, in search of the truth about her parentage.
While there she meets, and falls in love with local
lawyer/hotelier Ian McKendrick (Matter).
The tone is emotional.